The true story of the most beautiful woman in the world
I Am Divine is a documentary film directed by Jeffrey Schwarz.
Harris Glenn Milstead, aka Divine (1945-1988) was the
ultimate outsider turned underground hero.
Spitting in the face of the status quos of body image, gender identity, sexuality, and preconceived notions of beauty, Divine
succeeded in becoming an internationally recognized icon, recording artist, and character actor of stage and screen.
Glenn went from the often-mocked, schoolyard fat kid to underdog royalty, standing up for millions of gay men and
women, drag queens and punk rockers, and countless other socially ostracized misfits and freaks.
With a completely committed in-your-face style, he blurred the line between
performer and personality, and revolutionized pop culture.
Self (archive footage), played by Divine.
Self, played by John Waters.
Self, played by Ricki Lake.
Self, played by Lisa Jane Persky.
Self, played by Bruce Vilanch.
Self, played by Mink Stole.
I Am Divine is a 2013 American documentary film produced and directed by Jeffrey
Schwarz of the Los Angeles-based production company Automat Pictures.
The documentary focuses on the American actor, singer, and drag performer Divine (October 19, 1945 – March 7,
1988), born Harris Glenn Milstead, a lifelong friend and collaborator of filmmaker John Waters.
The film features extensive contemporary interviews with Waters, as well as Divine's
mother Frances Milstead, and surviving members of the Dreamlanders.
The film explores themes of transvestite, cross dresser, gay theme, gay artist.